Japanese Arts Lantern Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Japanese Arts Lantern Slide Collection
1900-1960
VRC 3002
Yale University Arts Library
5
15 boxes
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of Japanese arts of all periods, pre-historic to the mid-20th century. Includes architecture, painting, sculpture, arms and armor, calligraphy, ceramics, enamel, furniture, lacquer, metalwork and textiles.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of Japanese arts of all periods, pre-historic to the mid-20th century. Includes architecture, painting, sculpture, arms and armor, calligraphy, ceramics, enamel, furniture, lacquer, metalwork and textiles.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by medium. Further sub-divided by location or chronological period, and if known, by individual artist name.
Arts -- Japan; Arts, Japanese; Slides; Lantern slides; Reproductions
- Architecture (Box 1)
  - General (Box 1)
    - Various Titles (Box 1)
    - Bridges (Box 1)
    - Construction Details (Box 1)
    - Customs (Box 1)
    - Gardens (Box 1)
    - Houses (Box 1–2)
    - Landscapes (Box 2)
    - Lanterns (Box 2)
    - Palaces (Box 2)
    - Shinto Shrines (Box 2)
    - Temples (Box 2)
    - Pre-Historic (Box 2)
  - By location (Box 2)
    - Hakodate (Box 2)
    - Hakone (Box 2)
    - Ise (Box 2)
    - Itami (Box 2)
    - Itsukushima (Box 2)
    - Izumo (Box 2)
    - Kamakura (Box 3)
    - Kobe (Box 3)
    - Koyasan (Box 3)
      - Kongobuji (Box 3)
    - Kyoto (Box 3)
      - Various Titles (Box 3)
      - Castles (Box 3)
        - Nijo-jo (Box 3)
      - Palaces (Box 3)
        - Imperial Palace (Box 3)
        - Katsura Rikyu (Box 3)
          - Katsura Rikyu (Box 3)
          - Exteriors (Box 3)
          - Interiors (Box 3)
          - Gardens (Box 3)
          - Shokintei (Box 4)
          - Shugakuin (Box 4)
      - Temples (Box 4)
        - Various Titles (Box 4)
        - Chionin (Box 4)
        - Daigoji (Box 4)
        - Daitokuji (Box 4)
        - Hokaiji (Box 4)
        - Joruriji (Box 4)
        - Kiyomizudera (Box 4)
        - Nanzenji (Box 4)
        - Ninnaji (Box 4)
        - Nishi Honganji (Box 4)
        - Ryoanji (Box 4)
        - Sanjusangendo (Box 4)
        - Tenryuji (Box 4)
        - Mitoku, Tottori (Box 4)
        - Nagoya (Box 4)
          - Nagoya Castle (Box 4)
        - Nara (Box 4)
          - Various Titles (Box 4)
          - Shrines (Box 4)
            - Kasuga (Box 4)
          - Temples (Box 5)
            - Asukaji (Box 5)
            - Gangoji (Box 5)
            - Horyuji (Box 5)
            - Kofukuji (Box 5)
            - Muroji (Box 5)
            - Todaiji (Box 5)
              - Plans (Box 5)
              - Daibutsuden (Box 5)
              - Belfry (Box 5)
              - Hokkedo (Box 5)
              - Nandaimon (Box 5)
              - Toshodaiji (Box 5)
              - Yakushiji (Box 5)
        - Nikko (Box 5)
          - Various Titles (Box 5)
          - Toshogu (Box 5)
      - Osaka (Box 5)
      - Takaoka (Box 5)
      - Uji (Box 5)
        - Byodoin (Box 5)
- Painting (Box 6)
  - Prehistoric (Box 6)
  - Suiko, 553-650 CE (Box 6)
    - Horyuji (Box 6)
  - Tempyo, 710-794 (Box 6)
    - Various Titles (Box 6)
    - Shosoin (Box 6)
      - Various titles (Box 6)
      - Biwa (lutes) (Box 6)
      - Kako genzai inga kyo (Sutra of Past and Present Karma) (Box 6)
  - Jogan, 794-897 (Box 6)
    - Various Titles (Box 6)
    - Kongoka Mandara (Vajradhatu Mandala) (Box 6)
  - Fujiwara, 897-1185 (Box 7)
    - Unknown Artist (Box 7)
      - Various (Box 7)
      - Amitabha Triad (Box 7)
      - Byodoin Wall Paintings (Box 7)
      - Choju Jimbutsu Giga (Box 7)
      - Jigoku zoshi (Box 7)
      - Nezame Monogatari (Box 7)
      - Raiko Triptych (Box 7)
      - Yamai no soshi (Box 7)
      - Shigisan engi emaki (Box 7)
    - Known Artist (Box 7)
      - Tokiwa Mitsunaga (Box 7)
      - Fujiwara Munehiro (Box 7)
  - Kamakura, 1185-1336 (Box 8)
    - Unknown Artist (Box 8)
      - Various Titles (Box 8)
      - Heiji monogatari (Box 8)
      - Honen shonin gyojo (Box 8)
      - Kegon engi (Box 8)
      - Kitano Tenjin engi (Box 8)
      - Mongolian Invasion (Box 8)
      - Obusama Saburo Emaki (Box 8)
    - Known Artist (Box 8)
      - Fujiwara Tsunetaka (Box 8)
      - En-I (Box 8)
      - Takuma Eiga (Box 8)
      - Nobuzane Fujiwara (Box 8)
      - Rokurobe Rengyo (Box 8)
      - Takuma Shoga (Box 8)
      - Takanobu Fujiwara, 1141-1204 (Box 8)
  - Ashikaga, 1336-1568 (Box 8)
    - Unknown Artist (Box 8)
      - Various Titles (Box 8)
    - Known Artist (Box 8)
      - Gakuo (Box 8)
      - Naejima Soyu (Box 8)
      - Shokei (Box 8)
      - Geiami (Shingei), 1431-1485 (Box 8)
      - Korehisa (Box 8)
      - Mincho (Box 9)
      - Tosa Mitsunobu, 1434-1525 (Box 9)
      - Kano Motonobu, 1476-1559 (Box 9)
      - Sesshu, 1419-1506 (Box 9)
      - Shubun, fl. ca. 1420 (Box 9)
      - Soami, d. 1525 (Box 9)
      - Oguri Sotan, 1413-1481 (Box 9)
      - Yukimitsu, fl. 1360-1371 (Box 9)
      - Kano Yukinobu, 1513-1575 (Box 9)
  - Momoyama, 1568-1615 (Box 9)
    - Unknown Artist (Box 9)
      - Various Titles (Box 9)
    - Known Artist (Box 9)
      - Sanraku, Kano (Box 9)
      - Sansetsu, Kano (Box 9)
      - Eitoku, Kano, 1543-1590 (Box 9)
      - Koetsu Honnami, 1556-1637 (Box 9)
      - Tosa Mitsuyoshi, 1539-1613 (Box 9)
      - Nobukata (Box 9)
      - Shokado Shojo, 1584-1639 (Box 9)
      - Sotatsu, Tawaraya (Box 9)
      - Hasegawa Tohaku, 1539-1610 (Box 9)
      - Yusho, Kaiho, 1533-1615 (Box 9)
  - Tokugawa, 1615-1867 (Box 9)
    - Unknown Artist (Box 9)
      - Various Titles (Box 9)
      - Shuji Mandala (Box 9)
    - Known Artist (Box 9)
      - Buncho, Tani, 1764-1846 (Box 9)
      - Buson, Yosano, 1716-1783 (Box 9)
      - Goshun, Matsumura, 1752-1811 (Box 9)
      - Gyokudo, Urakami, 1745-1820 (Box 9)
      - Haranobu, Suzuki, 1725-1770 (Box 9)
      - Hoitsu, Sakai, 1761-1828 (Box 9)
      - Jakuchu, Ito, 1713-1800 (Box 9)
      - Kenzan, Ogata, 1663-1743 (Box 9)
      - Korin, Ogata (Box 9)
      - Koi, d. 1636 (Box 11)
      - Kyosai (Box 11)
      - Kaigetsudo (Box 11)
      - Matabei, Iwasa, 1578-1650 (Box 11)
      - Mitsuoki, Tosa, 1617-1691 (Box 11)
      - Musashi, Miyamoto, 1582-1645 (Box 11)
      - Naonobu, Kano, 1607-1650 (Box 11)
      - Okyo, Maruyama, 1732-1795 (Box 11)
      - Ritsuo, 1663-1747 (Box 11)
      - Sansetsu, Kano, 1589-1651 (Box 11)
      - Shohaku, 1730-1783 (Box 11)
      - Sosen, Mori, 1747-1821 (Box 11)
      - Susetsu, 1736-1804 (Box 11)
      - Suzuki Kiitsu, 1796-1858 (Box 11)
      - Kano Tanyu, 1602-1674 (Box 11)
      - Tessan, Mori, 1775-1841 (Box 11)
  - 20th century (Box 11)
    - Known Artist (Box 11)
      - Gyokudo Kawai, 1873-1957 (Box 11)
- Sculpture (Box 11)
  - Prehistoric (Box 11)
    - Various Titles (Box 11)
  - Suiko, 553-650 (Box 11)
    - Nara (Box 11)
      - Horyuji (Box 11)
  - Hakuho, 650-710 (Box 12)
    - Nara (Box 12)
    - Tokyo (Box 12)
  - Tempyo, 710-794 (Box 12)
    - Various Titles (Box 12)
    - Nara (Box 12)
      - Various Titles (Box 12)
      - Horyuji (Box 12)
      - Kofukuji (Box 12)
      - Shin-Yakushiji (Box 12)
      - Todaiji (Box 12)
    - Kyoto (Box 12)
  - Jogan, 794-897 (Box 12)
    - Various Titles (Box 12)
    - Kyoto (Box 12)
    - Nara (Box 12)
      - Gangoji (Box 12)
      - Hokkeji (Box 13)
      - Horyuji (Box 13)
      - Imperial Museum (Box 13)
      - Kofukuji (Box 13)
      - Yakushiji (Box 13)
    - Yamato (Box 13)
  - Fujiwara, 897-1185 (Box 13)
    - Various Titles (Box 13)
    - Nara (Box 13)
      - Horyuji (Box 13)
      - Yakushiji (Box 13)
    - Uji (Box 13)
      - Jocho, d. 10 (Box 13)
  - Kamakura, 1185-1336 (Box 13)
    - Various Titles (Box 13)
    - Kamakura (Box 13)
    - Kyoto (Box 13)
    - Nara (Box 13)
    - Known Artists (Box 13)
      - Jitsugen, ac. 1190-1198 (Box 13)
      - Jokei, ac. 1196-1200 (Box 13)
      - Kaikei, ac. 12th century (Box 13)
      - Koben, ac. 13th century (Box 13)
      - Tankei, ac. 13th century (Box 13)
      - Unkei, d. 1223 (Box 14)
  - Ashikaga, 1336-1568 (Box 14)
    - Various Titles (Box 14)
  - Momoyama, 1568-1615 (Box 14)
    - Various Titles (Box 14)
  - Tokugawa, 1615-1867 (Box 14)
    - Various Titles (Box 14)
  - Java (Box 14)
    - Various Titles (Box 14)
  - Korea (Box 14)
    - Various Titles (Box 14)
- Minor Arts (Box 14)
  - Shosoin Repository (Box 14)
    - Various Titles (Box 14)
  - Arms and Armor (Box 14)
    - Various Titles (Box 14)
  - Calligraphy (Box 14)
    - Various Titles (Box 14)
  - Ceramics (Box 14–15)
    - Various Titles (Box 15)
  - Enamels (Box 15)
    - Various Titles (Box 15)
  - Furniture (Box 15)
    - Various Titles (Box 15)
  - Lacquer (Box 15)
    - Various Titles (Box 15)
  - Metal (Box 15)
    - Various Titles (Box 15)
  - Textiles (Box 15)
    - Various Titles (Box 15)